VALLARASU SAMBATHKUMAR

vals@live.in | +91 9486 180 175 | linkedin.com/in/vallarasus | Chennai, India

SUMMARY

Lead Engineer with 15 years of experience in building applications for the web, mobile, and desktop. Built products, frameworks, and tooling for developers. Lead development and support teams through development and release cycles. Lead innovation and new helped with hiring, on-boarding and mentoring new hires.

SKILLS

- Angular - SQLite

- React Native - Postgresql, Sequelize

- React - WPF

- Node.js - Type Script, JavaScript

- Coherence - C# .Net - Openfin - Java - SQL - F#

EXPERIENCE

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER | WELLS FARGO - BANGALORE, INDIA | 01/2018 - CURRENT

- Coordinated a team of four in building low latency trading applications.
- Executed technology transformations.

TECH LEAD | HONEYWELL - BANGALORE, INDIA | 01/2014 - 01/2018

- Introduced new products, Built remote monitoring and fail-over.
- Lead product initiatives, and technology transformations.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER | DRS DATA SERVICE, United Kingdom | 01/2013 - 01/2014

- Developed applications and Unit tests with .Net and SQL
- On Contract

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | INGERSONL RAND - CHENNAI, INDIA | 01/2011 - 01/2013

- Implemented weather reporting and data visualization modules in .Net
- On Contract

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | SYNCFUSION - CHENNAI, INDIA | 01/2010 - 01/2011

- Lead development and Support efforts
- Built Products, frameworks, and tooling for .Net WPF and WinForms

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING - ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATIONS Syed Ammal Engineering College | Chennai | 01/2009 GPA: 78.5%

CERTIFICATIONS

AZURE FUNDAMENTALS, AZ-900